

# Serena Tomassetti

🛱 15th April 1989

O Zürich, Switzerland

் L'Aquila, Italy

C-Permit

#### **CONTACTS**

**&** +41 76 728 42 70

serenatomassetti.com

in linkedin.com/in/serena-tomassetti

#### **SKILLS**

HCI, User Research, User Interface, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Information Architecture, UX Writings, Usability Test.

## **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

Figma, Sketch, Invision, Axure, Balsamiq, Creative Cloud, Zeplin, Google Analytics, Look Back.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Italian: native

English: fluent (C1)

German: professional (B2)

#### **PASSIONATE ABOUT**

Design, art, photography, skiing,

hiking, traveling.

#### SUMMARY

Resourceful User Experience Designer with broad practice in design and customer experience. I promote a user centered approach across companies and build fruitful relationships with clients and colleagues. I am recognized for critical thinking, accuracy to details, self management and capacity to adapt quickly. I am a curious person, an hungry reader and traveler, with a high interest in technology and innovation.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **UX Designer • IptiQ By SwissRe**

Zürich • Mar 2021 - Present • Contract

Designed a new digital B2B2C product for our partner Ikea. Collaborated closely with all the project's stakeholders. User research, User tests, UI Design, Agile methodology.

## **UX Designer • Muume AG**

Zürich · Dec 2020 - Feb 2021 · Contract

Designed digital interfaces for B2B and B2C softwares in 3 break points. Collaborated closely with Head of Design, project managers and developers. User research. Agile methodology.

# **UX Designer • Visit Altopiano**

Rome (Remote) • Sep - Nov 2020 • Contract
Designed touristic mobile app for Visit Altopiano from research up to the implementation. Collaborated closely with stakeholders and developers.

# **UX Designer • Bar Voce**

Rome (Remote) • Apr - Jun 2020 • Contract

Designed digital strategy for Bar Voce's safe restart during the Covid-19 pandemic. Collaborated closely with stakeholders and developers.

#### **UX Designer • Freelance**

Zürich · Aug 2019 - Present

Designed digital user experiences in various freelance projects.

#### Brand Ambassador · Lindt & Sprüngli

Zürich • Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Sales and customer experience. Collaborated with marketing bridging observations and proposing solutions. Support on store layout, stock and visual merchandising.

#### **Promoter** • M.Prestige Promotions

Zürich • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Target sales for YSL, Dior, Chanel and customer experience. Trained on customer psychology and behavior from Brand Managers.

## Travel Designer • Ed è Subito Viaggi

Rome • Jan - Jul 2015

Designed tailored travel experiences, established long-term customer loyalty and returning customers. Identification of customer needs, customer experience and support.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **User Experience Nanodegree**

Udacity • 2020

Created an end-to-end digital user experience ready to be handed off for development.

- · User research for qualitative and quantitative data · Analysis and Synthesis of collected data
- Design Sprint Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype Style guide and Design library
- Usability test and Iterations.

# **User Experience Bootcamp**

Interaction Design Foundation • 2019 - 2020

Designed a Project Management Web app through 1 to 1 mentorship sessions and guidance.

- User Research Design Sprint Sitemap Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype
- Style guide and Design library.

# **Travel Experience Design**

Centro Turistico Studentesco - CTS, Italy • 2014

Lead the team for the design of a new travel itinerary in Brazil starting from the identification of a new travel concept until the prove of feasability.

• Market Research and Competitive Analysis • Travel Product ideation • Design of new itinerary • Prove of feasable implementation • Presentation of the project.

#### **Bachelor of Art**

**University of L'Aquila, Italy • 2008 - 2013**Cultural and Environmental Heritage.

## **Erasmus Exchange**

**University of Zagreb, Croatia • 2012 - 2013**Master's Thesis in History of Architecture.

#### **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

- UX Management: Strategy and Tactics, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021.
- Information Visualization: Getting dashboards right, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Gamification: Creating addictive user experiences, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Affordances: Designing intuitive user interfaces, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Accessibility: How to design for all, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Emotional Design: How to make products people will love, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Agile Software Development, University of Minnesota, 2020
- Human Computer Interaction- HCI, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- UI Design Patterns for succesful software, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20
- User Research Methods and Best Practices, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Mobile UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Design Thinking, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Fundamentals of Graphic Design, typography and storytelling, Californian University of Arts, 2019.
- Store Layout & Visual Merchandising, London University of Arts, 2018
- Travel Experience Design, CTS, 2014.